newstalk.ie 2016-11-26

# Privacy Policy | Newstalk

We will not monitor, edit or disclose any personal information about you without your prior consent. In the course of the Newstalk Nation Royalty Scheme (Newstalk Nation) we may acquire personal data and information about you which you have registered with us. When you give your personal details to us, we have a duty to keep these details private and safe. This process is known as data protection. Under data protection law, you have rights regarding the use of your personal details and we have certain responsibilities in how we handle this information.

In this regard, we undertake to only use your data in complete accordance with the following conditions: We will not rent or sell any data which may personally identify you to any third party. We may aggregate your data for disclosure to advertisers or business associates for promotion and marketing purposes. By way of example, we may disclose to an advertiser the percentage age groups of our members but in such an event we undertake to ensure that no such data could be used to personally identify you. We may share your data with related groups in the Communicorp group but only for the purposes of market profiling. This may mean that you could be contacted by a company within the Group for market profiling.

We may access your lists and related communications for technical processing and to address technical problems or service complaints. Certain data such as your password will never be disclosed. You are responsible for keeping your password confidential and for all activities that occur under your password or account. Please let us know of any unauthorised use of your password, or any other breach of security. We will clearly state why we are collecting personal information and how it will be used. At your request we will allow you inspect and edit any personal data relating to you.

We cannot ensure that private communication and other identifiable personal data will never be disclosed in ways not described in this section. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing) we may be forced to disclose the data to a government agency lawfully requesting the same or to any court acting in pursuance of its powers. We reserve the right to and you hereby agree to allow us to disclose any information about you to law enforcement, government officials or to any court or court officials as we in our sole discretion believe necessary or appropriate.

Nothing in this Agreement relating to the confidentiality of information shall prevent or hinder Newstalk from complying with its legal obligations as to disclosure or otherwise under the Data Protection Act 1988.

By joining the Newstalk Nation Programme you agree to allow us to communicate with you via email regarding Newstalk Nation earning and redemption opportunities. We will always use this communication method responsibly.

The Use Of 'Cookies'

In order to enable us to provide you with a personalised browsing experience, this site uses 'cookie' information collection technology. "Cookies" are small pieces of information that are issued to your computer when you enter a website. Cookies are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive, and they can be used for a wide range of purposes, such as identifying your computer's previous visits to this website, and to ascertain the most popular features of this website or providing access to certain site features. Disabling cookies could mean you are not able to use some features of the website.

Please note that if you choose to opt-out of receiving cookies, you may lose some features and / or functionality of newstalk.com, for example - you won't be able to login with Newstalk ID.

We use the Demographics and Interest Reporting features of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers, Visitors can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers by visiting the Ads Preferences Manager. 

Why Do We Use Cookies?

Like many other websites, this website uses cookies as they enable us to identify your computer when you visit this website. For example, cookies can make it possible for us to identify and automatically log in registered users of certain services on this website without the need for us to ask users for their registration details and password each time they visit.

We also use cookies to develop a clearer picture of which parts of this website are the most popular to its visitors, and your preferences. You are not obliged to accept cookies and you may amend your browser's settings to prevent it from accepting cookies.

If you have an Newstalk ID, a cookie on your computer lets us remember your user name and email address so you don't have to enter it again when you are commenting or writing a review.

For more information on how to manage cookies, including opting-out of functional cookies please visit:[http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)

When you use the newstalk.com website the following types of cookies can be set on your computer, smartphone or other devices:

Third party advertising

Advertisements appearing on this website may be posted by third parties who may use their own cookies and have their own privacy policies. Some examples of services that use these types of cookies include Google AdSense or DoubleClick.

For information on opting out of targeting and advertising cookies please visit:<http://www.youronlinechoices.com/ie/your-ad-choices>

Other third party cookies

Some cookies that have been set on our websites are not related to Newstalk or our partners. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube, Twitter, Polldaddy or Facebook, these service providers may set their own cookies on your web browser.

We do not control the use of these cookies and cannot access them due to the way that cookies work, as cookies can only be accessed by the party who originally set them. You should check the third party websites for more information about these cookies.

Feedback, Comments & Suggestions

If you have any queries about Our Privacy Policy or any queries about the protection of personal information we hold about you, please do not hesitate to contact us. Our address is Newstalk, Newstalk HQ Marconi House Digges Lane Dublin 2 Phone: 01 644 5100 Fax: 01 644 5101 or email us at [info@newstalk.com](mailto:info@newstalk.com)

If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy you should not submit your personal information on this website.

Mobile Application Privacy Policy December 2012

This privacy policy governs your use of a software application "Newstalk App" on a mobile device that was created by "Communicorp Digital"

This document explains how Communicorp Digital processes information about you which is personally identifiable ("your information") when you use the Newstalk Application.

Communicorp Digital is registered as a data controller for the purposes of the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003. If you have any queries about how we use Your Information or have a complaint, please contact us.

The Newstalk Application is home to shows like The Right Hook, Moncrieff, Breakfast, Lunchtime, Tom Dunne and Off The Ball. You can listen live to the best of independent talk radio, download and listen to podcasts, get the latest news and if you missed anything, find it on the archive player.

  1. The application includes:
  2. Full screen Newstalk TV.
  3. Podcasts download and play when offline.
  4. Airplay and External TV support added

Mobile Advertising:

Advertisements track whether there has been an engagement with the advert. However it does not track it down to individual level. In the case of certain adverts such as iPolls the ad will track whether your mobile device was previously used to vote in the iPoll. It does not track which way you voted.

Data capture in mobile:

The data to be collected for advertisements featuring competitions is defined by the advertiser. The competition entry form will clearly identify the information that is required from you for that competition. It is the user's decision to supply the information and determine whether you wish to proceed with your entry into the competition. Full terms and conditions applying to the competition and the capture of your data will be displayed on the competition entry form.

User Provided Information

The rich social features of the application require the use of a large set of Facebook functionality. The application seeks your consent to access and use your information from Facebook using the standard mandatory Facebook authorization process.

When entering a Competition within the Application you may be asked to provide all/any of the following:

  1. Name
  2. Email Address
  3. Telephone No.
  4. Postal Address
  5. Age where legally required i.e. Alcohol brand

Automatically Collected Information

In addition, the Application may collect certain information automatically, such as:

  1. Type of mobile device you use
  2. Your mobile devices unique app installation ID
  3. IP address of your mobile device,
  4. your mobile operating system,
  5. Type of mobile Internet browsers you use
  6. Information about the way you use the Application.

Does the Application collect precise real time location information of the device?

This Application does not collect precise information about the location of your mobile device.

MMA MOBILE APPLICATION

Do third parties see and/or have access to information obtained by the Application?

Yes. We will share your information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement.

We may disclose User Provided and Automatically Collected Information:

  1. To any suppliers and subcontractors in order to fulfil the service
  2. If we are under a duty to disclose or share your information in order to comply with any legal obligation or in order to enforce or apply the User Terms as applicable and other agreements;
  3. To third parties for marketing purposes only where you have consented to this.
  4. If Communicorp Digital is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of this information, as well as any choices you may have regarding this information
  5. This Application is supported via advertising, and collects data to help the Application serve ads e.g. whether you are using an iPhone or Android

MMA MOBILE APPLICATION

Data Retention Policy, Managing Your Information

We will retain User Provided data for as long as you use the Application and for a reasonable time thereafter. If you'd like us to delete User Provided Data that you have provided via the Application, please contact us [here](mailto:mailto:info@communicorpdigital.ie) and we will respond in a reasonable time.

Please note that some or all of the User Provided Data may be required in order for the Application to function properly, and we may be required to retain certain information by law.

Access to your information and corrections

You have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of such information, please [contact us](mailto:mailto:info@communicorpdigital.ie). You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate by contacting us. We hope you will be happy with the way we handle your information but if not you have the right to complain to the Office of the Irish Data Protection Commissioner - for more information visitwww.DataProtection.ie.

Security

Communicorp Digital is concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your information. We provide physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect information we process and maintain.

For example, we limit access to this information to authorised employees and contractors who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Application. Please be aware that, although we endeavour to provide reasonable security for information we process and maintain, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches.

Changes

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason.

We will notify you of any changes to our Privacy Policy by posting the new Privacy Policy here

You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes.

Your Consent

By using the Services, you are consenting to our processing of User Provided and Automatically Collection information as set forth in this Privacy Policy now and as amended by us. "Processing," means using cookies on a computer/hand held device or using or touching information in any way, including, but not limited to, collecting, storing, deleting, using, combining and disclosing information, all of which activities will take place in the Republic of Ireland (ROI). If you reside outside the ROI your information will be transferred to the ROI, and processed and stored there under the ROI privacy standards. By using the Application and providing information to us, you consent to such transfer to, and processing in, the ROI.

Contact us

  1. If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence;
  2. Any other information provided by you pursuant to your use of the Newstalk Application.

If you have any questions regarding privacy while using the Application, or have questions about our practices, please contact us [here](mailto:mailto:info@communicorpdigital.ie).
